Consider this image of a dog.
看看这幅小狗图片
A single region in this image,
图片中的单个区域
may have many different patterns that we want to detect.
可能具有很多需要我们检测的规律
Consider this region for instance,
例如这个区域
this region has teeth,
这个区域有牙齿
some whiskers, and a tongue.
几根胡须和舌头
In that case, to understand this image we
这样的话 要理解这幅图片
need filters for detecting all three of these characteristics.
我们就需要用于检测所有这三种特性的过滤器
One for each of teeth, whiskers, and tongue.
牙齿 胡须和舌头分别对应一个过滤器
Recall the case of a single convolutional filter,
还记得之前的单个卷积过滤器吗
adding another filter is probably exactly what you'd expect.
添加另一个过滤器可能完全一样
Where we just populate an additional collection of nodes in the convolutional layer.
我们只需填充另一组卷积层中的节点
This collection has its own shared set of
这个集合具有自己的共享权重集
weights that differ from the weights for the blue nodes above them.
与上方蓝色节点的权重不同
In fact, it's common to have tens to hundreds of these collections
实际上 在一个卷积层中拥有数十个或数百个
in a convolutional layer-- each corresponding to their own filter.
这种节点集合是很常见的 每个都对应自己的过滤器
Let's now execute some code to see what these collections look like.
我们现在运行一些代码 看看这些集合的代码如何
After all, each is formatted in the same way as an image,
毕竟 每个的形成方式都和图片的一样
namely as a matrix of values.
即值矩阵
We'll be visualizing the output of a Jupyter notebook.
我们将可视化 Jupyter notebook 的输出
If you like and you can follow along with the link below.
如果你愿意的话 可以点击下面的链接跟着操作
So, say we're working with an image of Udacity's self-driving car as input.
假设我们要处理的输入图片是优达学城的无人驾驶汽车
Let's use four filters,
我们使用四个过滤器
each four pixels high and four pixels wide.
每个都高 4 个像素 宽 4 个像素
Recall each filter will be convolved across the height and width
每个过滤器将在图片的宽和高上卷积
the image to produce an entire collection of nodes in the convolutional layer.
以在卷积层中形成整个节点集合
In this case, since we have four filters,
这里 因为我们有四个过滤器
we'll have four collections of nodes.
因此将有四组节点
In practice of for to each of
在实际操作中
these four collections is either feature maps or as activation maps.
我们将这四个集合分别称为特征映射或激活映射
When we visualize these feature maps,
当我们可视化这些特征映射时
we see that they look like filtered images.
我们看到它们看起来像过滤后的图片
That is we've taken all of the complicated dense information in
即我们从原始图片中提取出
the original image and in each of
所有复杂的密集信息
these four cases outputted a much simpler image with less information.
并在每个集合中输出信息更少的更简单图片
By peeking at the structure of the filters,
通过观察这些过滤器的结构
you can see that the first two filters discover vertical edges,
可以发现前两个过滤器发现了垂直边缘
where the last two detect horizontal edges in the image.
后两个过滤器检测到图片中的水平边缘
Remember that lighter values and the feature map
特征映射中浅色的值
mean that the pattern in the filter was detected in the image.
表示在图片中发现了过滤器中的规律
So can you match the lighter regions in each feature map with
你能将每个特征映射中的浅色区域
their corresponding areas in the original image?
与原始图片的相应区域进行匹配吗？
In this activation map for instance,
例如在这个激活映射中
we can see a clear white line defining the right edge of the car.
我们可以看到一条清晰的白色线条 表示汽车的右侧边缘
This is because all of
这是因为
the corresponding regions in the car image closely resemble the filter.
汽车图片中的所有对应区域与过滤器很相似
Where we have a vertical line of dark pixels
垂直浅色像素的左侧是
to the left of a vertical line of lighter pixels.
垂直深色像素线条
If you think about it you'll notice that edges in images appear as
如果思考下 会发现图片中的边缘
a line of lighter pixels next to a line of darker pixels.
显示为在深色像素旁边的浅色像素线条
This image for instance contains many regions that would be
例如这个图片包含很多可以被之前定义的
discovered or detected by one of the four filters we defined before.
四个过滤器之一发现或检测到的区域
Filters that function as edge detectors are very
在 CNN 中 充当边缘检测器的函数非常重要
important in CNNs and we'll revisit them later.
稍后我们会继续讲解
So now we know how to understand convolutional layers that have a grayscale images input.
现在我们知道什么是具有灰度图片输入的卷积层了
But what about color images?
那么彩色图片呢？
Well, we've seen that grayscale images are interpreted by
我们知道灰度图片被计算机解读为
the computer as a 2D array with height and width.
具有宽和高的二维数组
Color images are interpreted by the computer as a 3D array with height, width and depth.
彩色图片则被计算机解读为具有宽度 高度和深度的三维数组
In the case of RGB images,
对于 RGB 图片
the depth is three.
深度是 3
This 3D array is best conceptualized as a stack of three two-dimensional matrices,
这些三维矩阵可以理解为三个二维矩阵堆叠到了一起
where we have matrices corresponding to the red,
这些矩阵对应的是图片的红色
green, and blue channels of the image.
绿色和蓝色通道
So how do we perform a convolution on a color image?
那么如何对彩色图片进行卷积处理呢？
As was the case with grayscale images,
和灰度图片一样
we still move a filter horizontally and vertically across the image.
依然在图片上水平及垂直地移动过滤器
Only now the filter is itself three dimensional to have a value for
但是现在过滤器本身是三维的
each color channel at each horizontal and vertical location in the image array.
对于图片数组中每个水平和垂直位置的颜色通道都有一个值
Just as we think of the color image as a stack of three two-dimensional matrices,
就像我们将彩色图片看做三个二维矩阵的堆叠一样
you can also think of the filter as a stack of three two-dimensional matrices.
也可以将过滤器看做三个二维矩阵的堆叠
Both the color image and the filter have red,
彩色图片和过滤器都拥有红色
green, and blue channels.
绿色和蓝色通道
Now to obtain the values of the nodes in the feature map corresponding to this filter,
要从特征映射中获取对应于该过滤器的节点值
we do pretty much the same thing we did before.
流程和之前的差不多
Only now, our sum is over three times as many terms.
只是现在求和的项是之前的三倍
We emphasize that here we've depicted the calculation of the value of
这里计算的是彩色图片上一个过滤器的
a single node in a convolutional layer for one filter on a color image.
卷积层中一个节点的值
If we wanted to picture the case of a color image with multiple filters,
如果要表示具有多个过滤器的彩色图片
instead of having a single 3D array,
而不是对应一个过滤器的
which corresponds to one filter,
一个三维数组
we would define multiple 3D arrays-- each defining a filter.
我们需要定义多个三维数组 每个定义一个过滤器
Here we've depicted three filters,
这里我们描绘了三个过滤器
each is a 3D array that you can think of as a stack of three 2D arrays.
每个都是一个三维数组 可以看做三个二维数组的堆叠
Here's where it starts to get really cool.
现在到了精彩的部分了
You can think about each of the feature maps in a convolutional layer along
你可以将沿着相同线条的卷积层中的每个特征映射
the same lines as an image channel and stack them to get a 3D array.
看做一个图片通道 将它们堆叠就能获得三维数组
Then, we can use this 3D array as input to
然后可以将此三维数组当做输入
still another convolutional layer to discover
依然形成另一个卷积层
patterns within the patterns that we discovered in the first convolutional layer.
以便从我们在第一个卷积层中发现的规律中发现规律
We can then do this again to discover patterns within patterns within patterns.
然后可以继续这么做 从规律中发现规律 然后继续从规律中发现规律
Remember that in some sense convolutional layers
注意 从某种程度上来说
aren't too different from the dense layers that you saw in the previous section.
卷积层和你在上一部分见到的密集层区别不大
Dense layers are fully connected meaning that
密集层是完全连接的
the nodes are connected to every node in the previous layer.
意味着节点与前一层级中的每个节点相连
Convolutional layers are locally connected where
卷积层是局部相连的
their nodes are connected to only a small subset of the previous layers' nodes.
节点仅与上一层级中的一小部分节点相连
Convolutional layers also had this added perimeter sharing.
卷积层还具有参数共享特性
But in both cases,
但是对于卷积层
with convolutional and dense layers,
和密集层来说
inference works the same way.
推理的工作原理是一样的
Both have weights and biases that are initially randomly generated.
二者的权重和偏差一开始都是随机生成的
So in the case of CNNs where the weights take the form of convolutional filters,
对于 CNN 来说 权重是卷积过滤器形式
those filters are randomly generated and
这些过滤器是随机生成的
so are the patterns that they're initially designed to detect.
一开始检测的规律也是随机的
As with MLPs, when we construct to CNN we will always specify a loss function.
和 MLP 一样 当我们构建 CNN 时 始终会指定损失函数
In the case of multiclass classification,
对于多类别分类
this will be categorical cross-entropy loss.
将是分类交叉熵损失
Then as we train the model through back propagation,
然后通过反向传播训练模型
the filters are updated at each epic to take on values that minimize the loss function.
在每个 epoch 都会更新过滤器 以便设定可以最小化损失函数的值
In other words, the CNN determines what kind
换句话说 CNN 根据损失函数
of patterns it needs to detect based on the loss function.
确定它需要检测什么样的规律
We'll visualize these patterns later and see that for instance,
稍后我们将可视化这些规律
if our dataset contains dogs,
例如查看我们的数据集是否包含狗狗
the CNN is able to,
CNN 能够自己学习
on its own, learn filters that look like dogs.
看起来像狗狗的过滤器
So with CNNs to emphasize,
强调下 对于 CNN
we won't specify the values of the filters or
我们不会指定过滤器值
tell the CNN what kind of patterns it needs to detect.
或者告诉 CNN 它需要检测什么样的规律
These will be learned from the data.
而是从数据中学习